Cameron MacLeod

Computer Science Student

<u>cmacleod170@gmail.com</u>
<u>www.cameronmacleod.com</u>
https://github.com/notexactlyawe

Skills

Technologies: Python, .NET, Android, React, Java, C++

A final year university student on track for a first-class degree with a wide range of experience from internships and university. Interested in challenging roles that require both technical and soft skills.

Experience

Tenzo / Full Stack Intern

May 2019 - September 2019, London

Tenzo is a restaurant data analytics startup experiencing a period of high growth. Primarily worked on integrations with other software, but also web development as required. The position included a lot of responsibility and independent working.

Python Django, React, API integration

Bloomberg LP / Software Engineering Intern

July 2018 - September 2018, London

Worked on improving the reporting system for the Custom Indices team. Part of a team that embraced agile and focused on delivering small, high-value increments in a rapid cycle.

C#, SQL Server, Agile

Cambridge Consultants / Tech Scholar

September 2015 - August 2017, Cambridge

Took part in the placement year programme. Worked on projects across areas such as embedded devices, blockchain and computer vision. Returned following summer for two-month internship.

Embedded development, Python, Consulting R&D

Projects

CreatED 2018

CreatED was the UK's first student hackathon focused on hardware projects and hosted 100 people. I was an organiser responsible for sponsorship, workshops and event software. Raised over £7000 and delivered a well received event (95% 8/10 or higher overall participant satisfaction).

Sales, Leadership, Events

abracadabra - EuroPython 2016

Python implementation of the paper "An Industrial Strength Audio Search Algorithm" by the creators of Shazam. Gave a talk on the project at EuroPython 2016 in both English and Spanish, links are available.

Python, DSP, Public speaking

Education

University of Edinburgh / Computer Science BSc (Hons.)

2016 - 2020

Modules on programming, maths, data science and Russian (outside course).

Shrewsbury Sixth Form College / A Levels

2013 - 2015

Electronics, Maths, Spanish, Physics, Computing (AS), Further Maths (AS)

Awards

GreatUniHack 2016

First place overall

Won first prize with a hack called Wimphony. The project was an Android app that mapped wi-fi networks musically in VR.

Android, Unity

Young Rewired State Festival of Code 2014

Best in show (public vote)

Won Best in Show (public vote) with a smart coat hanger called Hook. Hook would tell you what to wear based on the weather for that day.

Python, APIs, Public speaking

Volunteering and extracurricular

Embedded and Robotics Society

May 2017 - May 2019

Co-founded a university society in second year and served as secretary for two years. The role involved a wide variety of work including planning and delivering events, obtaining sponsorship and writing educational materials. Leadership, Education, Embedded development

Startup Summit 2018

October 2018

Volunteered at a large startup conference in Edinburgh, mostly as a doorman/microphone runner for the talks.

Volunteering, Startups

cameronmacleod.com Blog

2016 - Present

Personal blog mostly around technical topics that arise day to day. Mostly done for enjoyment, but in the hope that other people will find it useful.

Technical writing, Communication